[{"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f6d", "question": "Which author first became famous under the pseudonym Norman Bean?", "answer": "Edgar Rice Burroughs", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cc", "question": "Which large animal can swim, but not jump?", "answer": "The elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392c2", "question": "What breed of dog was \"The Ugly Dachshund\" in the 1966 Disney film?", "answer": "A Great Dane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4c2", "question": "What is the world's fastest growing plant?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3f28c73aa70ea0b70afd", "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5907229d3745b36be7303a01", "question": "The nearest permanently inhabited place to the North Pole is part of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5af25d77b63e5727cf5a4865", "question": "Vanilla Ice's song, \"Ice Ice Baby\" samples the bassline from which song?", "answer": "\"Under Pressure\" by Queen and David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e910021d7247dfc0fa0030c", "question": "The first U.S. state park was created in which state?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff2115a31a458464a93c441", "question": "Which American author was awarded both the Nobel Prize in Literature and Presidential Medal of Freedom?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd2d9772596a59cbdfbd3c5", "question": "Which Wild West crime was last documented on December 5, 1916?", "answer": "Stagecoach robbery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a822", "question": "When facing Mount Rushmore, which president's head is farthest to your left?", "answer": "George Washington", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b32", "question": "Who is the one-eyed giant of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b505", "question": "What two skills make up the winter biathlon?", "answer": "Cross-country skiing and target shooting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef96e56ce05a3942286ea3", "question": "In the first televised baseball game, the Cincinnati Reds played what team?", "answer": "Brooklyn Dodgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad46", "question": "What US president was known as \"Father of the Constitution\"?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b332", "question": "Which country hosted the Olympic Games In 2004?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d7", "question": "In Norse mythology, what was the name of the monster killed by Beowulf?", "answer": "Grendel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c658", "question": "Mach refers to the speed of what?", "answer": "Sound", "category": "science"}, {"id": "592eae8cf83302ff91e4648a", "question": "What animal is a Chester White?", "answer": "A pig", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ac1", "question": "The book \"The Second Sex\" was written by who?", "answer": "Simone de Beauvoir", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eba", "question": "What happens to Neo twice in a row that clues Trinity in to a glitch in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "A black cat passes him", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "592eb04ef83302ff91e4649b", "question": "What time period does the 1972 film \"The Godfather\" span?", "answer": "1945 to 1955", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd96b7c23c87fd04dd15e1c", "question": "What US President tried to set up his daughter with Prince Charles?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59a1a2d112f2a7826b9b8720", "question": "In what 1988 did film David Bowie play Pontius Pilate?", "answer": "Last Temptation of Christ", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89d", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after a married couple?", "answer": "Curium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c316", "question": "What is one of pi's rational approximations?", "answer": "22/7", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe902c601dd7bf43be5e86b", "question": "If you want to raise Thor's hammer what must you be?", "answer": "Worthy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb3a", "question": "A bridle is a piece of headgear often used to control what animal?", "answer": "A horse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ad", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Granite State\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60121a9563c99d48cd169b04", "question": "What is the common name for enuresis?", "answer": "Bedwetting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b33c", "question": "What is the name of Agrippa's husband, who she poisoned?", "answer": "Claudius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded059ea2747c8aff16d26", "question": "In which city is the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015dffffe83fe1f2a824b84", "question": "Which extinction event was caused by human activity?", "answer": "Holocene extinction", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b443", "question": "Who was Joseph Merrick better known as?", "answer": "Elephant Man", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab68", "question": "In what Australian state would you find the major port town Fremantle?", "answer": "Western Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f5", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c2e", "question": "What book series was written and illustrated by Jeff Kinney?", "answer": "Diary of a Wimpy Kid", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc9", "question": "Who is the Norse god of verility, prosperity, and sun?", "answer": "Frey", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefc3f26ce05a3942286f29", "question": "Colin Hay is the founder and lead vocalist for what rock band?", "answer": "Men at Work", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a058", "question": "Adrenalize, Retro Active, and Pyromania are albums from which British hard rock band?", "answer": "Def Leppard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff666ab52a821ff76ae8afa", "question": "Which labor standard were the striking workers out to achieve which eventually led to the Haymarket Affair in the US?", "answer": "8-Hour Work Day", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b4cae662d71a53650ff0", "question": "What literary genre is Edgar Allen Poe credited with starting?", "answer": "Crime novels", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397c7", "question": "What are the Blues Brothers' first names?", "answer": "Jake and Elwood", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133920c", "question": "In which TV show is the local fast-food restaurant called \"The Chum Bucket\"?", "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e7", "question": "What tree measurement do foresters usually make at 4 feet above ground level?", "answer": "Girth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b819", "question": "What sport has official rules to cover \"tea intervals\"?", "answer": "Cricket", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59a552b23e1c6f9840ba319b", "question": "Which country has the calling code 82?", "answer": "South Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb6327e83c707845b2124", "question": "Which land mammal has the most teeth?", "answer": "Giant armadillo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff259af31a458464a93c46e", "question": "If a person's candle flame goes off on the night of Halloween, it indicates that the person is with what?", "answer": "A ghost", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b4be01dd7bf43be5e7c6", "question": "Why were bowler hats invented?", "answer": "To protect gamekeepers from low branches", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae0f", "question": "What city hosted the 2008 Summer Olympics?", "answer": "Beijing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60173e3544491cbd7c5a17ae", "question": "According to U.S. history, which is the \"date which will live in infamy\"?", "answer": "Dec. 7, 1941 -- The date the U.S. naval base, Pearl Harbor, was the target of a devastating surprise attack by Japanese forces.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ecae269790ded87bb38fd88", "question": "In biology, what does RNA stand for?", "answer": "Ribonucleic Acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adbf", "question": "Which two public figures were assassinated in the United States in 1968?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. and Robert Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59e804edde59ea584496fea7", "question": "Archie Moore was World Champion in what sport from 1952 to 1962?", "answer": "Boxing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e07afe83fe1f2a824b8d", "question": "Which Old West figure became sports editor for the \"New York Morning Telegraph?\"", "answer": "William Barclay \"Bat\" Masterson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339959", "question": "Who played Frankenstein\u2019s monster in the 1931 movie \"Frankenstein\"?", "answer": "Boris Karloff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0b34ce662d71a53650fdd", "question": "Who wrote the opening line, \"All children, except one, grow up\"?", "answer": "J.M. Barrie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a324", "question": "What was the full name of Mangum P.I.?", "answer": "Thomas Magnum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c16", "question": "The fictional town of South Park is located in which US state?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f0", "question": "What are the three traditional ingredients of shortbread cookies?", "answer": "Butter, flour and sugar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfd", "question": "What term for stable, well-established stocks comes from a $10 bet in poker?", "answer": "Blue chips", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c018", "question": "What is the Italian name for squid in a restaurant?\u00a0", "answer": "Calamari\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7791ff048f679a45abca", "question": "How many watts is one horsepower?", "answer": "746", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2df", "question": "What year was actor Arthur Stanley Jefferson born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82c", "question": "Prosciutto is derived from the meat of what animal?", "answer": "Pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ec244b8dc25ca9e12ef637", "question": "In which European country would you find the town of Eupen?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5e", "question": "Who did Prince Charles wed in a \"wedding fit for a prince\" in 2005?", "answer": "Camilla Parker Bowles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb61505dad637d903c882f", "question": "In 2014, a criminal gang in China used the chemical rongalite to flood the market with which contaminated food?", "answer": "Tofu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ae95a3574a5ce6b56b8257", "question": "What are formed by Orogeny?", "answer": "Mountains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5d7", "question": "What is the atomic number of the element uranium?", "answer": "92", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d4", "question": "Which US state has the most shoreline along the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a8", "question": "What was the name of Alexander the Great's famous horse?", "answer": "Bucephalas", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac65", "question": "What name was Eva Peron known by?", "answer": "Evita", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c2b63c99d48cd169b12", "question": "Norman Rockwell painted 323 covers for which magazine?", "answer": "\"Saturday Evening Post\" -- The magazine featured Rockwell\u2019s work from 1916 to 1963.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b64f01dd7bf43be5e7d9", "question": "Which famous author worked as an entertainment director on a cruise line?", "answer": "J.D. Salinger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f9", "question": "What type of animal was selected to test out the first electric toothbrush?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd0", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"E\"?", "answer": "Echo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a64e", "question": "What is the Napa Valley best known for?", "answer": "Wine", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fffa77173838c5c8a417f38", "question": "What are people who love eating ice called?", "answer": "Pagophagiacs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59ae9363574a5ce6b56b823a", "question": "What was Queen Victoria's first name?", "answer": "Alexandrina", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339429", "question": "Who is \"The Jerk\"?", "answer": "Steve Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e05cfe83fe1f2a824b8b", "question": "What German political leader was known as the \"Iron Chancellor\"?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f06", "question": "What movie character is a \"sweet transvestite from Trans-sexual, Transylvania\"?", "answer": "Frank N. Furter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c19a", "question": "The \"canebrake\", \"timber\" and \"pygmy\" are types of what?", "answer": "Rattlesnakes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab960586faa38a764be51a", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af25653b63e5727cf5a483c", "question": "What century was the model construction system \"Meccano\" created by Frank Hornby?", "answer": "19th century", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac86", "question": "What country gave the Statue of Liberty to the US?", "answer": "France", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a9f", "question": "What US state is the setting for \"The Cleveland Show\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f3", "question": "In The Simpsons, who do Jumbo and Kearney usually hang around with?", "answer": "Dolph", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a669", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Land of Enchantment\"?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d7", "question": "What is added to cognac to make a Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "White creme de menthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c064", "question": "In the video game \"God of War\", which mythological character must Kratos defeat at the end to finish the game?", "answer": "Ares (the God of War)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600244894be4723ccac221a5", "question": "Romanesque art prevailed during what time period?", "answer": "Romanesque art is the art of Europe from approximately 1000 AD to the rise of the Gothic style in the 13th century.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ea", "question": "Excluding vowels with macrons, how many letters are in the Hawaiian alphabet?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133916b", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9299574a5ce6b56b822f", "question": "Who wrote \"The Rose Tattoo\"?", "answer": "Tennessee Williams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2c7", "question": "What Briton with an American wife was the governor of the Bahamas during World War II?", "answer": "King Edward VIII", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c944", "question": "Who invented the kinetoscope?", "answer": "Louis Le Prince", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5921fcdca4edfd43a087adc3", "question": "What number is represented by \"V\" in Roman numerals?", "answer": "5", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f93", "question": "What is the name of Alice's pet cat?", "answer": "Dinah", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f0b0ff048f679a45aaa3", "question": "Sociophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Social evaluation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febbc977e83c707845b214e", "question": "How long did it take the director of the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" to write the script?", "answer": "Eight weeks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339099", "question": "Hera is the goddess of what?", "answer": "Women and marriage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea4241ff048f679a45ab77", "question": "What is the opening of a camera lens, which controls the amount of light?", "answer": "Aperture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae05", "question": "What did JFK call \"the most hazardous and dangerous and greatest adventure on which man has ever embarked\"?", "answer": "Putting a man on the moon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded166ea2747c8aff16d32", "question": "Mead is made primarily from what?", "answer": "Honey", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ea", "question": "Which is the highest waterfall?", "answer": "Angel Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c4", "question": "The opera Aida was commissioned to mark what event?", "answer": "Opening of the Khedivial Opera House", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015fcecfe83fe1f2a824c47", "question": "What skill characterized the \"Homo habilis\" species?", "answer": "Tool-making", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339254", "question": "Who was the first character Johnny Depp portrayed in more than one movie?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89f", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the moon?", "answer": "Selenium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc8a0ec223966ae8f8891", "question": "Pro golfers rack up points as they compete for what corporate-sponsored cup that was first awarded in 2007?", "answer": "The FedEx Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990f3c7fa5fdd6dd25324dc", "question": "What's the principal river of Ireland?", "answer": "Shannon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bca", "question": "What year was Boy George born in?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c0", "question": "What animal has the highest blood pressure of any animal?", "answer": "The giraffe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac5", "question": "On what 1990s TV show did the characters sometimes hang out at a bar called Shooters?", "answer": "Melrose Place", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05b", "question": "What is the name of Amy Winehouse's first album?", "answer": "Frank", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded085ea2747c8aff16d29", "question": "Ireland's River Shannon drains which basin?", "answer": "Shannon River Basin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d78e2596a59cbdfbd3b7", "question": "John Adams wanted the President to have which controversial title?", "answer": "His Highness", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c5", "question": "What Irish city's name is Gaelic for \"black pool\"?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5b", "question": "The shoe-obsessed Spats Colombo is the villain of what 1959 comedy?", "answer": "Some Like It Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6008dcacf4f3bc4a292f861b", "question": "How many times was Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. arrested?", "answer": "29 (Many of the charges against him were illegitimate and the result of widespread, systemic racism.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae97", "question": "To what tribe did Sitting Bull belong?", "answer": "Sioux", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c203877e98cb97778983", "question": "Who named the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597743a3284458f1d785442a", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c64", "question": "What Stephen King novel features an evil clown named Pennywise?", "answer": "It", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a08f", "question": "Who recorded the albums \"Cuts Both Ways\", and \"Into The Light\"?", "answer": "Gloria Estefan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b991", "question": "Mean Joe Greene helped what team win four Super Bowls?", "answer": "Pittsburgh Steelers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6e4da9e54d890926f6c4", "question": "Where was the first Broadway theater in New York City?", "answer": "Financial District (Broadway's history began in a 280-person theater on Nassau Street in the Financial District.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b3a04fda37788a9a1dc4", "question": "What year did Agatha Christie publish the novel \"Sparkling Cyanide\"?", "answer": "1945", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b356", "question": "Who opened the first \"cinema\" in Paris in 1895?", "answer": "The Lumiere Brothers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c7ae0775fa611bce67dc", "question": "What does ABV stand for in the beer industry?", "answer": "Alcohol By Volume", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8cd1794b094db915830a4", "question": "How many Academy Award nominations did Leonardo DiCaprio receive before finally winning the award for Best Actor in 2016?", "answer": "6", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba191874c93a3298b2128", "question": "Of which US state was Jimmy Carter Governor before he became president?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d9e", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Independence Day\"?", "answer": "Bill Pullman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "593c4a66b8198b9a2b07795c", "question": "Who played the male lead role in the film \"Avatar\"?", "answer": "Sam Worthington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a197", "question": "In the video game \"Darksiders\", which of the Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse do you play?", "answer": "War", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008c0acf842fa4c4ba969c", "question": "Mysophobia is the irrational fear of what?", "answer": "Contamination", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc5d", "question": "What popular architect designed the Guggenheim Museum of Modern Art?", "answer": "Frank Lloyd Wright", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c2694f032c0db195b481", "question": "How old was Catherine of Aragon when she was betrothed to Prince Arthur?", "answer": "Catherine was three years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9fe", "question": "Hawaii's Kalaupapa was known as a refuge for those suffering from what disease?", "answer": "Leprosy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc8b16de0eb824d4052fe", "question": "Which U.S. state named the cherry as its official state fruit?", "answer": "Utah -- A 1997 school class campaigned on behalf of cherries, an important crop in Utah, and got the nod from state legislators.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339999", "question": "What jazz saxophonist was nicknamed \"Bird\"?", "answer": "Charlie Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a943", "question": "What does \"Lo Stivale\", the local name for the Italian peninsula, mean in Italian?", "answer": "The boot", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339798", "question": "Who did Michael Jackson marry in May 1994?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Pressley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ffb9a3a3a814d89068c67", "question": "Which singer and songwritter was born Farrokh Bulsara in 1946?", "answer": "Freddie Mercury", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015e242fe83fe1f2a824b9d", "question": "On which region of the Soviet Union did Hitler place the highest priority?", "answer": "Ukraine and southern Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d3d", "question": "What actor died nine days after completing his final movie \"Soylent Green\"?", "answer": "Edward G. Robinson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c49afbde8045e484669e", "question": "Where will you likely find an oxpecker bird?", "answer": "On a rhino\u2019s back -- They will perch on a rhino's back and eat bugs off its skin, and also give a warning if they see a predator.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75d", "question": "What is the deepest lake in the world?", "answer": "Lake Baikal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afdb", "question": "The Battle of Midway occurred in the Pacific Ocean during what war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fac", "question": "What TV title character lived at 485 Mapleton Drive, Mayfield?", "answer": "Beaver Cleaver", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95f77ccba3ffe45786e6", "question": "Whose autobiography was entitled \"The Sport of Queens\"?", "answer": "Dick Francis'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d74", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"There and Back Again\"?", "answer": "The Hobbit", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c35a", "question": "What is the most obvious physical difference between snails and slugs?", "answer": "The shell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4a", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aaa", "question": "Who wrote the Christmas novel, The Lost Angel in 1971?", "answer": "Elizabeth Goudge", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c057", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Italy?", "answer": "Italian sparrow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0cf2596a59cbdfbd381", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7df", "question": "What are the bumps on the tongue that carry the taste buds called?", "answer": "Papillae", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8cc0ec223966ae8f884e", "question": "What movie inspired the director of \"The Shawshank Redemption\" into using a voice-over narration.", "answer": "\"Goodfellas\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cb53bb53d1af658864d7", "question": "In the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", how many drummers are drumming?", "answer": "Twelve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c886", "question": "Rennet, an enzyme-filled juice from animal stomachs, is used in the making of what?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5952413d736d4be723796b61", "question": "Which superhero was created by Mike Young, as a way to help his child sleep at night?", "answer": "SuperTed", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a30220565ad31a57c7b0", "question": "What did the letters on the first license plates represent?", "answer": "The owner's initials", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ae863427f28483af1e7fdc9", "question": "What was the last imperial dynasty of China?", "answer": "Qing Dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a9e95a47ccba3ffe45786e2", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Rigoletto\"?", "answer": "Giuseppe Verdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015ec33fe83fe1f2a824bfc", "question": "What was the name of the earliest form of paper currency?", "answer": "\"Flying Money\" -- used during China's Tang dynasty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8c5", "question": "What desert is home to the Ahaggar and Tibesti mountains?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967e", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the Simpson's stove?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c3a", "question": "Which basketball superstar had a major role in the 1996 movie \"Space Jam\"?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25b9fb63e5727cf5a485a", "question": "Which English band had the hit song \"Unbelievable\"?", "answer": "EMF", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf1", "question": "Who wrote \"Slaughterhouse Five\"?", "answer": "Kurt Vonnegut", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffe4bcb47818f5674af01b3", "question": "What is the name of the book the movie \"Goodfellas\" is based on?", "answer": "\"Wiseguy: Life in a Mafia Family\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956e", "question": "What year was Robert Liberman's, All I Want for Christmas released?", "answer": "1991", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c073", "question": "What is a \"Blenheim Orange\"?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133914f", "question": "Who was the Greek god of volcanoes?", "answer": "Hephaestus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e4", "question": "What was the last name of Eddie Murphy\u2019s character in the movie \u201cTrading Places\u201d?", "answer": "Valentine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904a471cf93664eb10486c3", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is Katchoo\u2019s full name?", "answer": "Katina Marie Choovanski", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec259a8dc25ca9e12ef640", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Fahrenheit 451\"?", "answer": "Ray Bradbury", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5c88e71422f44c2d77a29c44", "question": "What is Shakespeare\u2019s shortest tragedy?", "answer": "Macbeth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a49d", "question": "Which European country's name is derived from the term \"hollow land\"?", "answer": "Holland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b228", "question": "What city was Elizabeth Short killed in?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e1", "question": "What is a one-humped camel called?", "answer": "Dromedary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b8", "question": "What Miss America Pageant winner turned in her tiara on July 23, 1984?", "answer": "Vanessa Williams", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87e", "question": "What four notes are represented on the four strings of a ukulele?", "answer": "G, C, E, A", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3231a6bf195a31e15d7386", "question": "Who shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize with Menachem Begin?", "answer": "Mohamed Anwar Al-Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b3731c1c3f17ccc40c8e2a", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "art"}, {"id": "58c8a7fd90aac110e416708a", "question": "What year was Lasse Hallstrom\u2019s film \"The Cider House Rules\" released?", "answer": "1999", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cbc0877e98cb97778a1e", "question": "In which country is the Casa Rosada?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd72", "question": "What is sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aba", "question": "For what movie did Cher win a Best Actress Oscar?", "answer": "Moonstruck", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbd", "question": "What model was married to musician Travis Barker?", "answer": "Shanna Moakler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909cd39bb53d1af658864e7", "question": "What gives traditional eggnog its frothy texture?", "answer": "Whipped eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fdffbdd1cf6db9ac4808cf9", "question": "What is the only country capital that contains a national park?", "answer": "Nairobi, Kenya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58c8a62390aac110e416707b", "question": "What popular tea is named after an 1830\u2019s United Kingdom Prime Minister?", "answer": "Earl Grey tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133badc", "question": "A person described as a \"towhead\" has what color hair?", "answer": "Blonde", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbb", "question": "On \"The Simpsons\", what character's wife is voiced by SNL's Jan Hooks?", "answer": "Apu's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaf0", "question": "What is the capital of the US state Wisconsin?", "answer": "Madison", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339940", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a fever of what temperature?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b66501dd7bf43be5e7db", "question": "What kind of animal is a hellbender?", "answer": "Salamander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339389", "question": "What is Indiana Jones' first name?", "answer": "Henry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f1687cf7c52aae91cc07c8", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab23", "question": "Which ocean does Mozambique has water access to?", "answer": "Indian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb80", "question": "Which one of tennis' Grand Slam tournaments did Pete Sampras never win?", "answer": "French Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff518b1ff04d658268c9300", "question": "For what is the Siberian Husky dog named Balto famous?", "answer": "When diphtheria hit Nome, Alaska in 1925, Balto led the mush team of Siberian Huskies carrying serum on the last leg of the trek.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa9b", "question": "What is the capital of the Republic of Nauru?", "answer": "Yaren", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecd41bec223966ae8f88ca", "question": "Some of the musical compositions for \"The Hateful Eight\" are unused scores from what movie?", "answer": "\"The Thing\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59decff3ea2747c8aff16d22", "question": "Illyngophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Veritgo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8838ec223966ae8f881c", "question": "What is the name of the legendary videogame designer who created the Mario franchise?", "answer": "Shigeru Miyamoto", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3f0528b5801b8f54a7fba", "question": "Paris\u2019 Notre Dame Cathedral was built on the ruins of what?", "answer": "A pagan temple to Jupiter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd2", "question": "What country was the birthplace of architects Alvar Aalto and Eero Saarinen?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf4e", "question": "Angelo Sicilano better know as who?", "answer": "Charles Atlas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390aa", "question": "What US state was author J. D. Salinger born in?", "answer": "New York", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b690", "question": "The tuxedo got its name from what?", "answer": "A town in New York", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ce", "question": "A tetrapod is a creature with how many feet?", "answer": "Four", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d5", "question": "If it is 1:00 a.m. in Alaska, what would the time be in New York?", "answer": "5:00 a.m.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fb08453cf631c2414a13b49", "question": "Which actor is killed off in the opening scene of the 1996 movie \"Scream\"?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acfb", "question": "Which famous family owned a cat named Socks?", "answer": "The Clintons", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbf", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Billy Idol?", "answer": "Mony Mony", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c25a", "question": "What is 400 in Roman numerals?", "answer": "CD", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b27", "question": "Who is credited with writing the first detective story, \"The Murders in the Rue Morgue\"?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc4", "question": "In 1939, Buck Ewing became the first Major League Baseball player from what position elected to the Hall of Fame?", "answer": "Catcher", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339830", "question": "What movie, directed by the Coen brothers, won an Oscar for \"Best Picture\" in 2008?", "answer": "No Country for Old Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ee", "question": "In The Simpsons, what is the name of the studio where Krusty's show is taped?", "answer": "Krustylu Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcb", "question": "What's the ancient Greek word for \"great city\"?", "answer": "Megalopolis", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed7f9a72b906b34e3cec", "question": "Who discovered the mathematical system of logarithms?", "answer": "John Napier", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd92ce347d002c297e4cb", "question": "What is \"Three King's Day\" also known as?", "answer": "Epiphany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f20", "question": "Who has been played in a movie by both Rosemary Murphy and Jennifer Jason Leigh?", "answer": "Dorothy Parker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be72", "question": "What is the Darlington Raceway also known as?", "answer": "The Track Too Tough to Tame", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c045", "question": "What's the triangular Asian pastry containing spiced meat?", "answer": "Samosa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00d", "question": "The Titanic sank while on its way to what city?", "answer": "New York", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e7", "question": "What does a pedometer count?", "answer": "Steps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133945a", "question": "Who does Eddie Murphy trade places with in the 1983 movie \"Trading Places\"?", "answer": "Dan Aykroyd", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e28", "question": "Who is Kate Hudson's mother?", "answer": "Goldie Hawn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f1", "question": "Who made his directorial debut with the 1966 movie \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Mike Nichols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf9a", "question": "In the standard game of Scrabble, what is the value of the letters \"Q\" and \"Z\"?", "answer": "10", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ea", "question": "\"The 10 days that shook the world\" refers to what country\u2019s revolution?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e63", "question": "Who revealed he was HIV-positive in his 1995 autobiography \"Breaking the Surface\"?", "answer": "Greg Louganis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf28", "question": "The pound cake got its name from the pound of what ingredient that it contains?", "answer": "Butter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f8", "question": "What explorer disappeared in 1928 while on a rescue mission for survivors of the crashed airship \"Italia\"?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339810", "question": "What was rapper Rick Ross' occupation prior to becoming a hip hop artist?", "answer": "Correctional officer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81c58d0de9af39e9d4683", "question": "What were acorns used to create during the Civil War?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c8c5fbde8045e48466e0", "question": "Most flowers have an odd number of what?", "answer": "Petals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ca88877e98cb97778a06", "question": "What country is made up of 3,000 islands, the largest being Honshu, Hokkaido, Kyushu and Shikoku?", "answer": "Japan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe52f861bf59ab7d2e38115", "question": "What is the largest Starbucks beverage size?", "answer": "Trenta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb67", "question": "What is the name of the six-pointed star which is the symbol of Judaism?", "answer": "Star of David", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ab0", "question": "What composer/writer team wrote, A Winters Tale?", "answer": "Mike Batt/Tim Rice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fef", "question": "What cartoon character is named for Princess Dala's diamond in a 1963 film?", "answer": "The Pink Panther", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd3", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"J\"?", "answer": "Juliett", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c7", "question": "Who was the first American astronaut to orbit the Earth, circling it three times in 1962?", "answer": "John Glenn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cefc100948005ec986edce2", "question": "Who is the ninth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Yves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b23c", "question": "What royal subject married Marie Antoinette?", "answer": "Louis XVI", "category": "history"}]